knouroozi@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Github

University of Waterloo Systems Design Engineering Student | Software, Product, Growth

Impactful and creative University of Waterloo full stack engineer with experience building software products used by 35+ million users. Committed to self-improvement. Self-taught programmer since junior year of high school!

Youngest graduate of Bitmaker Full-Stack Rails bootcamp (Toronto) at age 16. Got his first software job at #paid on the 3rd day of the bootcamp by demoing his real-time Slack clone that he had learned to build before the bootcamp had even started.

Software Products & Impact (>35M users impacted):

Wambo.ai brings smiles to people's faces – AI powered lip sync app (0 to 35M downloads in 2 months),

Conversify – LinkedIn automation (300 users, \$6K MRR),

Author of CSV.js (1.5k GitHub stars),

Consulting for Parker (YC W19) & SMBs

Areas of expertise includes both front-end and back-end skills:

JavaScript (React) • Python • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Ruby & Rails • Elixir & Phoenix • Git • Unix • Docker • AWS Cloud Entrepreneurial • Work Ethic • Growth Mindset • Driven • Problem Solving • Teamwork • Communication • Energetic

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer, Staffing Software | TimeSaved Inc., Toronto, Canada

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

4-month intern at software company supporting development team with front-end projects.

• Based on Figma designs, created a complete developer-friendly React component library using Styled Components in 7 weeks. Custom NodeJS build scripts for assets. Led development on a React Native application using Expo.

Software Engineering Intern, Consulting | Human Capital, San Francisco, United States

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

4-month intern at venture capital firm with \$500M AUM working on tech consulting for financial portfolio company.

• Productionized data science models and analysis for Forbes 500 bank resulting in millions of incremental revenues. Created a developer experience with Docker and Ubuntu services. Developed ETL pipelines using Python and Luigi.

Lead Full-Stack Developer, Creator Media | #paid, Toronto, Canada

July 2016 - March 2019

2.5 years as full-time software developer after high school and interim CTO (Aug '17 – Jan '18) of a Series A startup with 25 employees.

- Recognized for excellent code quality. Mentored interns and junior developers.
- Spearheaded design and development of V2 of the company's web app through user research and stakeholder management of C-levels and VPs to finalize UX designs.
- Served as interim CTO for 6 months to lead a new 3-person engineering team of junior and intermediate developers through technical mentorship.
- Developed and launched V2 of the company's web app with an AJAX and SCSS front-end and developed the back-end architecture using Test-Driven Development, Rails, and PostgreSQL. Increased important company KPI by 40%.
- Developed a social network scraping microservice with a custom job-processing framework with Elixir, Python, and MongoDB to power ad performance analytics driving client dashboard. Scaled from 1,800 queries per minute to 18,000.

Education

Bachelor of Applied Science, Systems Design Engineering University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Canada

Class of 2023

Algorithms & Data Structures, UX Design, Rapid Prototyping